《金刚》
∮ I'm sittir on top of the world. ∮
∮ 我正坐在世界的顶端 ∮
∮ I'm rollir along. ∮
∮ 我在摇摆 ∮
∮ Yes, rollir along. ∮
∮ 是的 在摇摆 ∮
∮ And I'm quittir the blues of the world. ∮
∮ 我正退离尘世的阴霾 ∮
∮ I'm singir a song. ∮
∮ 我唱着一首歌 ∮
∮ Yes, singir a song. ∮
∮ 是的 唱一首歌 ∮
∮ Glory hallelujah! I just told the parson. ∮
∮ 多美妙 哈里路亚   我曾跟牧师说 ∮
∮ Hey, Par, get ready to call. ∮
∮ 嘿 牧师 是时候召唤了 ∮
∮ Just like Hunpty Dunpty. ∮
∮ 就像蛋人那样 ∮
∮ I'm gonna fall. ∮
∮ 我要摔跟头了 ∮
∮ And I'm sittir on top of the world. ∮
∮ 我坐在世界的顶端 ∮
∮ I'm rollir along. ∮
∮ 我在摇摆 ∮
∮ Rollir along. ∮
∮ 在摇摆 ∮
∮ Don't want any nillions. ∮
∮ 不想要个几百万 ∮
∮ I'm gettir ny share. ∮
∮ 我有自己的财产 ∮
∮ I've only got one suit just one. ∮
∮ 我只有一套西装 就一套 ∮
Move along.
走啊
∮ That's all I can wear. ∮
∮ 这是我所有能穿的 ∮
∮ A bundle of noney. ∮
∮ 一捆钞票 ∮
∮ Don't nake ne feel gay. ∮
∮ 不会让我感到快乐 ∮
∮ A sweet little honey. ∮
∮ 一点甜甜的蜂蜜 ∮
∮ Is naking ne say. ∮
∮ 就可以让我说 ∮
∮ And I'm sittir, sittir on top, top of the world. ∮
∮ 我正坐在  坐在世界的顶端 ∮
∮ I'm rollir along. ∮
∮ 我在摇摆 ∮
∮ Rollir along. ∮
∮ 在摇摆 ∮
∮ And I'm quittir quittir the blues blues of the world. ∮
∮ 我正退离  退离尘世的阴霾 ∮
∮ I'm singir a song. ∮
∮ 我唱着一首歌 ∮
∮ Yes, singir a song. ∮
∮ 是的  唱一首歌 ∮
∮ Glory hallelujah! I just told the parson. ∮
∮ 多美妙 哈里路亚    我曾跟牧师说 ∮
∮ Hey, Par, get ready to call. ∮
∮ 嘿 牧师 是时候召唤了 ∮
∮ Just like Hunpty Dunpty. ∮
∮ 就像蛋人那样 ∮
∮ I'm gonna fall. ∮
∮ 我要摔跟头了 ∮
∮ Yeah! I'm sittir on top, top of the world. ∮
∮ 是啊 我正坐在世界的顶端 ∮
Oh!
哦!
∮ I'm rollir along. ∮
∮ 我在摇摆 ∮
∮ Rollir along. ∮
∮ 在摇摆 ∮
That's a funny one. Isn't that funnier?
这个喷嚏挺滑稽  是不是比以前的滑稽一些?
It's hysterical, Manny.
令人捧腹  曼尼
As long as we're laughing...
只要我们还在笑...
we won't cry over the box office.
就不会为了票房而哭
Talk about depressing.
说到沮丧
Twenty girls in feather boas prancing around like circus ponies.
20个姑娘头顶羽毛冠  象马戏团的小马一样昂首阔步
That's depressing.
那才真叫令人沮丧呢
I love a good chorus line.
我喜欢好的合唱团
(《隔绝》 杰克·德里斯库著)
- What's this?   - It's a play.
- 这是什么?  - 是出话剧
Who wrote it, Annie?
谁写的  安妮?
Some guy. Driscoll.
一个叫德莱斯库的
Driscoll.
德莱斯库
From the Federal Theatre.
联邦剧院的
Don't knock it, honey. At least they got an audience.
别太挑剔了  亲爱的  至少还有观众看他们的戏
It'll pick up. Isn't that right, Manny?
会好起来的  不是吗  曼尼?
It always does.
总是会好起来的
See you tomorrow.
明天见
The trick is to start to build right from the back of your throat.
窍门是从喉咙后部开始酝酿
Works well out through the nose, too.
从鼻子打出来也挺不错
Have you eaten today?
你今天吃东西了吗?
Oh...
哦...
I'm not hungry. Don't worry about me.
我不是很饿  不用担心我
Hey.
嘿
You're all I've got.
我现在只有你了
Come on, take me to dinner.
来吧  带我去吃晚饭
Okay.
好吧
You think the kitchen will still be open on Third?
第三街上的餐厅现在还没关门吧?
Soup and biscuits. Perfect.
汤和饼干  太好了
(剧院无限期关闭 等候进一步通知)
(安·丹劳 哈里·汉克尔 联合出演《公园漫步》现已取消)
Harry, what's going on?
哈里  这是怎么回事?
- Hey, open up! We work here.   - Not anymore, lady.
- 嘿  开门  我们在这里上班  - 不用再来了  女士
It's all right for you. We haven't had a paycheck in two weeks.
对你来说是没什么  可是我们两个星期没发工资了
How we gonna eat?
我们拿什么去吃饭?
- They're not getting away with this!   - They just did.
- 他们不能就这么跑了!  - 他们已经跑了
Ann, it's no use.
安  没用的
The show, it's over. It's done.
演出完了  结束了  完结了
I'm done.
我也完结了
I'm leaving, Annie.
我要走了  安妮
I'm going back to Chicago.
我要回芝加哥去了
I'm sorry.
对不起
I'm sorry, Annie.
对不起  安妮
Ever since you were small, people been letting you down.
从你小时候开始人们就不断让你失望
You gotta think of yourself now.
你现在得为自己想想
You should try out for that part.
你应该去试试那个角色
Oh, I know what you're thinking.
噢  我知道你在想什么
Every time you reach out for something you care about...
每当你去争取一样心爱的东西...
fate comes along and snatches it away.
命运之手就将它从你面前夺走
But not this time, Annie.
不过这一次不会的  安妮
Not this time.
这一次不会的
- Oh, hello, Mr. Weston.   - Oh, jeez.
- 哦  你好  威斯顿先生  - 噢  上帝!
Look, miss, I told you already, call my office.
听着  小姐  我已经跟你说过了  给我办公室打电话
Leave your resume with my secretary.
把你的简历给我的秘书
Now, why would I want to do that when we can talk about it in person?
我们可以面谈的情况下  我还有必要那么做吗?
Because that's what a smart girl would do.
因为一个聪明的女孩子会那么做的
But I already sent you my resume. You returned it unopened.
可我已经把简历给你了  你没有打开就退回来了
What can I say? Jack Driscoll's very particular about who he works with.
我能怎么办?杰克·德里斯库对演员是非常挑剔的
Please, just an audition. That's all I'm asking.
求你  就一次试镜而已  这是我所有的请求
Jesus, you don't give up, do you?
上帝啊  你不会放弃的  是吧?
Mr. Weston, I know this role backwards.
威斯顿先生  我对那个角色烂熟于胸
Well, that's too bad, 'cause we just gave the part to someone else.
呃  太糟了  我们刚把那个角色给了别人
I'm sorry, kid. The play is cast.
抱歉  孩子  这出戏已经满员了
I know times are tough.
我知道现在生计艰难
You want my advice?
想听我的建议吗?
Use what you got. You're not bad-looking.
用用你的本钱  你长得不难看
A girl like you doesn't have to starve.
你这样的女孩子不至于挨饿
There's a new place. It just opened.
有个新地方  刚刚开业
Now listen, princess, this gig ain't the Palace, you understand?
现在听着  公主殿下  这地方可不是什么宫殿  明白吗?
Ask for Kenny K. Tell him I sent you.
找肯尼·凯  就说是我叫你去的
Just play the date, take the money...
把戏做好  把钱拿到手...
forget you was ever there.
然后忘记你曾经去过那里
How much more is there?
还有多长?
Another five reels.
还有五盘胶片
Lights up.
开灯!
This is it?
就是这个?
This is what we get for our $40,000, Denam?
丹汉姆  就是这花了我们四万美元?
Another one of your safari pictures?
你的另一部冒险电影?
You promised us romantic scenes with Bruce Baxter and Maureen McKenzie!
你向我们许诺说
会有布鲁斯·巴克斯特和玛琳·麦肯济的浪漫场面
Come on, fellows, you know the deal.
少来了  伙计们  你们清楚我们的协议
We agreed to push Maureers start date...
我们都同意用玛琳的第一次约会做卖点...
so she could get her teeth fixed.
那样她就可以给她的牙整形了
It's not the principle of the thing, it's the money.
这不是原则的问题  是钱的问题
Carl, you've been in production for over two months.
卡尔  你已经开拍两个月了
Trust me, Bruce and Maureen are gonna steam up the screen...
相信我  只要一上船...
once we get them on the ship.
布鲁斯和玛琳就会开始在银幕上大放光彩了
What ship?
什么船?
The one that we hired to get to the location.
就是我们租的  要载我们去目的地的那条船
What location? Carl! You're supposed to be shooting on the back lot.
什么目的地  卡尔!你本应该在布景上拍的
Yes, I understand that.
是的  我明白
But, fellows, we're not making that film anymore...
伙计们  不过我们现在不拍那部电影了...
and I'll tell you why.
我来告诉你们为什么
The story has changed. The script has been rewritten.
故事改变了  剧本改写了
Life intervened.
真实的生活介入了
I've come into possession of a map.
我得到了一份地图
The sole surviving record of an uncharted island.
一座连海图上都没有的小岛  唯一一份现存的证据
A place that was thought to exist only in myth.
一个被认为只在神话里存在的地方
Until now.
直到今天
Whoa, Carl, slow down.
喂  卡尔  慢点
Is he asking for more money?
他是要更多的钱吗?
He's asking us to fund a wild-goose chase.
他是让我们掏钱赞助竹篮打水
I'm talking about a primitive world never before seen by man.
我所说的是一个原始世界  从没有人见过
The ruins of an entire civilization.
一个完整文明的遗迹
The most spectacular thing you've ever seen.
你们所见过的最壮观的景象
That's where I'll shoot my picture.
那里才是我的片场
Will there be boobies?
那会有奶子吗?
Boobies?
奶子?
Jigglies. Jiblonkas. Bazooms.
颤动的乳房  煽情的镜头
In my experience, people only go to these films...
根据我的经验  大家都是奔着...
to observe the undraped form of the native girls.
土著姑娘的裸体去看这种电影的
What are you, an idiot?
你是白痴吗?
You think they asked De Mille if he would waste his time on nudie shots?
你觉得他们会问德米尔  他会不会浪费时间在裸体镜头上?
No! They respected the filmmaker. They showed some class.
不会的  他们尊重电影工作者!他们是有品味的
Not that you'd know what that means, you cheap lowlife!
你当然不会明白  贱种!
Would you step out for a moment, Carl?
你能不能出去一会儿  卡尔?
Zelman and Associates.
索尔曼联合公司
Give me that, quick.
把那个给我  快点
You won't like it. It's non-alcoholic.
你不会喜欢的  这里面没有酒精
Preston, you have a lot to learn about the motion picture business.
普雷斯顿  关于电影工业你还有很多东西要学!
Don't write him off, fellows. He's hotheaded, sure...
不要把他打入冷宫  伙计们  毫无疑问他是头脑发热...
but Carl Denam's made some interesting pictures.
不过卡尔·丹汉姆还是拍过一些很有趣的作品
He's had a lot of near-success.
他有很多作品都...接近成功
He's a preening self-promoter.
他是个自我标榜的自大狂
An ambitious no-talent. The guy's got "loser" written all over him.
他有野心  但是没有才华  全身都透着失败
I understand your disappointment...
我可以理解你的失望...
He can't direct. He doesn't have the smarts.
他根本不会导演  他根本没那个脑子
He's washed up. It's all over town.
他算是完蛋了  地球人都知道
This jumped-up little turd's gonna bankrupt us.
这个跳梁小丑会让我们破产的
The animal footage has value.
这些关于动物的样片能卖出价钱吗?
Sure. Universal are desperate for stock footage.
当然  环球公司非常想要资料片镜头
Then sell it! Scrap the picture.
那就卖了它  取消拍摄
We got to retrieve something from this debacle.
我们得从这次惨败中收回点什么
Get him back in.
让他进来
Mr. Denam.
丹汉姆先生
I want the cast and crew on the ship within the hour.
我需要剧组人员和船员一小时内上船
No, Carl, you can't do this.
不  卡尔  你不能这么干
Tell them the studio pressured us into an early departure.
告诉他们制片方催我们提早出发
- It's not ethical!   - What are they gonna do, sue me?
- 这是不合法的  - 你想怎么着?告我  嗯?
They can get in line.
让他们排队去吧
I'm not gonna let them kill my film.
我不会让他们就这样砍掉我的电影
You realize that none of the camera equipment is on board?
你知不知道船上现在一件摄像设备都没有?
We have no permits, no visas.
我们没有许可  没有签证
That's why I have you, Preston.
这就是我雇你的理由  普雷斯顿
We have no insurance, we have no foreign currency.
我们没有保险  没有外国货币
In fact, we have no currency of any kind.
实际上我们什么货币也没有
He's there.
他在那儿
- Get in there.   - Who's gonna pay for the ship?
- 进去!  - 谁来付船的费用?
Get in.
进去!
- You get out of there! Come here!   - Step on it! Step on it!
- 你给我出来!出来!  - 踩油门!踩油门!
Get out! You're finished, Denam!
滚出来!你完了  丹汉姆!
Don't worry, Preston. I've had a lot of practice at this.
别担心  这样的场面我见的多了
I'm real good at crapping the crappers.
以恶制恶  这个我最拿手
Red Label, 80% proof...
80度的红牌威士忌...
to be packed in a crate marked "lemonade."
装在标记"柠檬水"的箱子里
You got it.
好的
Tell Maureen she doesn't have six hours to put on her face.
告诉玛琳  她可没有六个小时的时间化妆
If she wants to be in this picture, she's gotta be on that boat.
如果她想演这部电影的话  她就得上船
She doesn't wanna be in this picture.
她不想演这部电影
- Maureen pulled out.   - She pulled out?
- 玛琳不干了  - 她不干了?
Yesterday. I told you.
昨天的事  我告诉你了
You said we were shooting in Singapore, right?
你是跟她说我们要在新加坡拍  对吧?
That's what you told her.
你是这么跟她说的吧?
Yeah, but we're not shooting in Singapore.
我知道  可我们不在新加坡拍啊
God damn it, Preston, all you had to do was look her in the eye and lie.
该死的  普雷斯顿  你只需要看着她的眼睛扯个谎就行了
I got to get to a phone, talk to harlow's people.
我得找个电话  和哈劳的经纪人谈谈
She's unavailable.
哈劳没有空档
Myrna Loy? Clara Bow? Mae West?
梅那·罗伊?克莱儿·波?梅·韦斯?
You'll never get her into a size four.
她哪能穿得下4号衣服?
You gotta get a girl that'll fit into Maureers costumes.
你得找个能穿玛琳的戏服的女孩子
Fay's a size four.
菲是穿4号
Yes, she is, but she's doing a picture with RKO.
没错  可她现在正拍着一部雷电华公司的片子
Cooper, huh?
库珀是吗?
I might have known.
我应该想到的
You're not listening. We got to delay the shoot.
你根本没听我说  我们得推迟计划
Shut production down. We can't sail tonight.
暂停拍摄  今晚我们走不了
Not an option. Carl.
没门!卡尔
I said I'd find a girl.
我说了我能找到那个女孩子
For God's sake, Preston, think like a winner!
看在上帝的份上  普雷斯顿  你需要有成功者的思维方式
Call Jack. I need that goddamn screenplay!
给杰克打电话  我需要那个该死的剧本
Defeat is always momentary.
失败永远只是暂时性的
(仅限成人)
What?
怎么了?
(艳舞秀 所有座位25美分)
Hey! You gonna pay for this?
嘿!你要为这个付钱的
Excuse me.
打扰一下
Ma'am, I think you dropped this.
女士  我想你掉了这个
Vaudeville, huh?
歌舞杂耍  是吗?
I worked vaudeville once. That is a tough audience.
我参与过一回  观众非常挑剔
If you don't kill them fast, they kill you.
你不尽快搞定他们  他们就会搞定你
Mr. Denam...
丹汉姆先生...
I want you to know...
我想告诉你...
that I'm not in the habit of accepting charity from strangers.
我不是习惯于接受陌生人施舍的人
Or, for that matter...
或者换句话说...
taking things that don't belong to me.
拿不属于我的东西
It was obviously a terrible misunderstanding.
刚才显然是可怕的误解
It's just that I haven't been paid in a while.
只是我已经很长时间没有拿到过工资了
That's awful. Anyway, Ann... May I call you Ann?
太糟了  不管怎样  安... 我可以称呼你安吗?
You wouldn't happen to be a size four, by any chance?
有没有什么可能  你是穿4号的衣服?
No, no. Oh, God, no.
不  不  上帝  不
You've got me all wrong. Miss Darrow, please.
你完全误会我了  丹劳小姐  拜托
I'm not that type of person at all.
我根本不是你想象的那种人
What type of person are you?
那么你是哪种人?
I'm someone you can trust, Ann. I'm a movie producer.
我是你可以信任的人  安  我是个电影制片人
Believe me, I am on the level. No funny business. Please sit down.
相信我  我和那些低级趣味绝对不是一个档次  请坐
Please. Please.
拜托  拜托
Okay.
好的
Ann, I want you to imagine...
安  我要你想象...
a handsome explorer bound for the Far East.
一个前往远东的英俊探险家
You're filming in the Far East?
你们要在远东拍摄?
Singapore.
新加坡
On board ship, he meets a mysterious girl.
在船上  他遇到了一个神秘的女郎
She's beautiful, she's fragile, haunted.
她迷人  纤弱  心神不宁
And she can't escape the feeling that forces beyond her control...
她无法摆脱这样一种感觉  一种她无法控制的力量...
are compelling her down a road from which she cannot draw back.
在将她推向一段不归路
It's as if her whole life has been a prelude to this moment...
就好像她的前半生都只是这一刻的序幕...
this fateful meeting that changes everything.
这改变了一切的  宿命的相遇
And sure enough, against her better judgment...
理所当然地  有违她理性的判断...
She falls in love.
她坠入了爱河
Yes.
没错
But she doesn't trust it.
但她对这段感情并没有信心
She's not even sure if she believes in love.
她甚至不能确定  她是不是相信真爱的存在
Uh...
呃...
really?
是吗?
If she loves someone, it's doomed.
如果她爱上一个人  命中注定是没有结局的
Why is that?
为什么呢?
Good things never last, Mr. Denam.
美好的事物从来都是短暂的  丹汉姆先生
So you're interested. Good. That's settled, then.
那么你是感兴趣的  好  这个就算说定了
Now, I don't wanna rush you, but we are under some time pressure.
我不想催你  但是我们在时间方面比较紧迫
- Well, I really...   - Ann, I'm telling you...
- 呃  我真的...  - 安!跟你说吧...
you're perfect. Look at you.
你是最完美的人选  看看你
You're the saddest girl I've ever met.
你是我见过的最悲情的女孩子
You're gonna make them weep, Ann. You're gonna break their hearts.
你能让他们哭泣  安  你能让他们心碎
See, that's where you're wrong, Mr. Denam.
看  丹汉姆先生  这就是你搞错的地方
I make people laugh, that's what I do.
我的工作是让人们笑
Good luck with your picture.
祝你的电影好运
Ann? Miss Darrow, please!
安  丹劳小姐  拜托
I'm offering you money.
我会付你给钱的
Adventure, fame, the thrill of a lifetime, and a long sea voyage.
冒险  名誉  值得一生回味的经历  还有海上的长途旅行
You want to read a script?
你想要看剧本的话?
Jack Driscoll's turning in a draft as we speak.
我们谈话的同时  杰克·德里斯库正要交稿呢
Jack Driscoll?
杰克·德里斯库?
Sure. Why?
当然  怎么了?
Wait. You know him?
等等  你认识他?
No, not personally. I've seen his plays.
哦  不认识  我看过他的剧作
What a writer, huh? And let me tell you, Ann...
出色的作家  对吗?我告诉你吧  安...
Jack Driscoll does not want just anyone starring in this picture.
杰克·德里斯库可不希望随便什么人来演他的电影
He said to me, "Carl...
他对我说:“卡尔...
somewhere out there is a woman born to play this role."
有个女孩子是为了这个角色而生的”
And as soon as I saw you, I knew.
我一看到你  就明白了
Knew what?
明白什么?
It was always going to be you.
那个女孩子只可能是你
- How much do I owe you?   - Make it a quarter.
- 我还欠你多少?  - 25美分
Keep the change.
零钱不用找了
Is this the moving picture ship?
这就是我们的摄影船?
Not exactly.
不完全是
It's actually this one over here.
实际上是这边的这艘
(冒险号)
Don't let appearances deceive you. It's much more spacious on board.
不要被表面现象蒙蔽了  船上实际宽敞许多
- Is this all of the equipment?   - Yeah.
- 这就是所有设备?  - 对
- This is all of it?   - Yeah.
- 全都在这里了?  - 对
- We're taking the Bell & howell?   - Yeah.
- 我们带上"贝灵巧"影像设备了吗?  - 是的
- Good. You got all the lenses?   - Sure.
- 很好  你拿了所有的镜头?  - 当然
- Carl!   - Yes!
- 卡尔?  - 我在这里
- Get it on board, fellows.   - come on.
- 上船吧  伙计们  快  - 来吧
It's bad, it's bad.
不好了  不好了
They're on their way. I've just had word.
他们正在路上  我刚刚听说
- Who?   - Men in uniform.
- 谁?  - 穿制服的
The studio called the cops.
电影公司叫了警察
Englehorn! Cast off!
安格霍恩!解缆!
Hoist up the mainsail, raise the anchor...
升帆  起锚...
whatever the hell it is you do. We gotta leave!
随便你怎么办  我们得出发了!
I cannot do that.
这个我办不到
We are waiting on the manifest.
我们在等舱单
What? Who? English, please.
等谁?请说英语  谢谢
Paperwork, Mr. Denam.
必须的文件  丹汉姆先生
I'll give you another $1,000 to leave now.
现在走的话我再给你一千
You haven't given me the first $1,000 yet.
开始的一千你还没有给呢
Can we talk about this later?
我们能不能以后再说?
Can't you see we're in the company of a VIP guest?
你没看见我们有贵宾在这里吗?
Ma'am.
女士
Ann Darrow.
我是安·丹劳
So you are ready for this voyage, Miss Darrow?
那么你准备好这次旅行了  丹劳小姐?
Sure.
当然
Nervous?
紧张吗?
Nervous? No.
紧张?不紧张
Why? Should I be?
为什么这么问?我应该紧张吗?
It isn't every woman who would take such a risk.
不是每个女人都愿意冒这样的险
Why don't I show Miss Darrow to her cabin?
为什么不让我来领丹劳小姐去她的舱位呢?
Wonderful idea. Thank you, Preston.
好主意  谢谢  普雷斯顿
Miss Darrow, if you would just...
丹劳小姐  如果您不介意...
hi. My name is Preston. Carl's assistant.
嗨  我叫普雷斯顿  卡尔的助手
$2,000. It's a deal. Will you take a check?
说好了两千  你收支票吗?
Do I have a choice?
我有其他选择吗?
Please follow me.
请跟我来
If there's anything that you... Excuse me, fellows.
如果你有任何需要... 借过一下  伙计们
If there's anything that you need, please don't hesitate to ask.
如果你有任何需要  请尽管开口
Oh, Jesus! Jack, you scared me.
噢  上帝!杰克  你吓死我了
Listen. If anyone comes to the door, don't open it. You haven't seen me.
听着  如果有任何人来敲门  别开  你也从来没有见过我
Say I got depressed and committed suicide.
就说我得了抑郁症自杀了
Say I stuck my head down the toilet.
说我把头浸在了马桶里
- You want one?   - No. I can't stay, Carl.
- 想来点吗?  - 不行  卡尔  我得走了
I got a rehearsal for which I am now three hours late.
我有个排练  已经迟到三个小时了
- What's this?   - It's the script.
- 这是什么?  - 剧本
This is a script?
这就是剧本?
Jack, this is 15 pages.
杰克  只有15页
I know, but they're good. You've got 15 good pages there, Carl.
我知道  可它们都很精彩  你拿到了精彩的15页  卡尔
I'm supposed to be making a feature-length picture.
我可是要拍一部全长的电影
You told me I had more time. I'm sorry. Look, I gotta go.
你原来跟我说还有更多时间的  抱歉  我得走了
No, Jack, you can't do this to me. I have a beginning...
不行  杰克  你不能这么对我  我有了开端...
but I need a middle and an end. I gotta have something to shoot.
可我需要经过和结局  我得有东西可拍
Look, you got my notes. I got to go, pal. See you.
听着  你有我的注释  我得走了  朋友  回头见
All right, fine. We might as well settle up.
好  好吧  你也许想了结一下
You're gonna pay me?
你要付我钱?
I'm not gonna stiff a friend.
不会让朋友吃亏的
I've never known you to volunteer cash before.
我从来不知道你还会主动给人钱
How's $2,000 sound?
两千怎么样?
Sounds great.
太好了
I thought it might.
我觉得也是
- Sounds great.   - Okay.
- 太好了  - 好吧
Raise the spring line!
拉起缆绳!
Watch the aft!
注意船尾!
And voila.
好了
Thanks.
谢了
You've written "two grand."
卡尔  你...你写的是"两千"
So I did. Sorry about that. Let's start from the beginning.
可不是嘛  抱歉  我们从头再写一次
"Two thousand dollars."
"贰仟美元"
It is the 29th, isn't it?
今天是29号  对吗?
Oh, come on, it's the 25th. It's the 25th.
少来  是25号  是25号
God, I'm sorry. It'll just take a sec.
上帝  真抱歉  只需要多花点时间
Never mind, Carl. Just pay me when you get back.
行了  卡尔  等你回来再付我钱吧
All right.
好吧
Your cabin is the last on the left, Mr. Baxter.
巴克斯特先生  您的舱位在左手边最后一间
And may I just say how excited we are to have you back with us, sir?
请允许我表达对您回到我们中间的兴奋之情
Be a sport and lend a hand here, would you?
省省吧  帮把手好吗?
Excuse me. I'm trying to... I gotta get...
抱歉  我得... 我必需要下...
Christ!
上帝!
Appreciate the help, fellow.
非常感谢你的帮助  伙计
Let me get the door for you.
我来给您开门
Welcome to your stateroom, sir.
欢迎来到您的客房  先生
Dead slow ahead both, Mr. Hayes.
双机极低速前进  赫斯先生
Dead slow ahead both, Captain.
船长  双机微速前进
Oh, Christ!
哦  该死
God damn it!
妈的!
I keep telling you, Jack, there's no money in theater.
我一直在告诫你  杰克  在剧院是赚不到钱的
Oh, no! No!
噢  不  不
You're much better off sticking with film.
你最好还是来干电影
I don't do it for the money, Carl.
卡尔  我干这个不是为了钱
I happen to love the theater.
我碰巧爱上了剧院
No, you don't.
不  你并不爱
If you really loved it...
如果你真爱的话...
you would have jumped.
刚才就跳下去了
You! This is your fault!
是你!这都是你的错!
This room very comfortable. Plenty dim light, fresh straw.
这里非常舒适的  有充足的昏黄光线  新鲜的干草
Jesus. What do you keep down here?
天  这下面装的是什么?
Lion, tiger, hippo, you name it.
狮子  老虎  河马  应有尽有
You sell them to zoos?
卖给动物园吗?
Zoo, circus.
动物园  马戏团
Skipper get big money for rare animal.
船长卖珍稀动物赚了不少钱哪
Careful. Camel have bad accident on floor.
小心  地板上有骆驼尿
Stain unremovable.
擦不掉的污迹
Skipper catch any wild animal you want.
船长可以抓到你想要的任何动物
He'll do you real good price on white rhino.
你想要白犀牛的话他可以给你个好价钱
Choy.
老崔!
My apologies for not being able to offer you a cabin.
没能给您提供舱位我非常抱歉
Have you found an enclosure to your taste?
找到符合您品味的笼子了吗?
Spoiled for choice.
怎么选都烂
What are you, Mr. Driscoll? A lion?
您是什么呢  德里斯库先生?狮子?
Or a chimpanzee?
还是黑猩猩?
I'll take this one.
我就要这一间吧
(氯仿)
I told you to lock it up.
我告诉过你要锁起来
- Sorry, Skipper. Lumpy said...   - Lumpy doesn't give the orders!
- 对不起  船长  兰皮说...  - 这里不是兰皮发号施令!
What are you trying to do? Put the whole ship to sleep?
你要干什么?想要整船人都睡着吗?
Get them out of here.
把它们搬走
(主演: 布鲁斯 巴克斯特)
(亚马逊部落新娘)
- Compliments of the chef.   - Okay.
- 厨师的特别奉献  - 好的
Oh, Christ. Oh, God.
噢  上帝  俺的神啊
Lamb's brains in walnut sauce.
羊脑配核桃味汁
Jimmy.
吉米
You run those ropes up on deck like I told you?
你照我说的把绳子绕在甲板上了吗?
Doing it now, Mr. Hayes.
现在就去  赫斯先生
How about you return Mr. Driscoll's pen first?
先把德里斯库先生的钢笔还给他怎么样?
He don't mean no harm.
他没有恶意的
Thanks.
谢谢
- I'll keep him out of your way.   - It's okay.
- 我不会让他再来了  - 没关系的
It's just that he likes it down here.
他很喜欢这个地方
It's where I found him four years ago.
这里也是四年以前我发现他的地方
Stowed away in one of them back cages.
装在后面的一个笼子里
His arm was broken in two places.
胳膊两处骨折
He was wilder than half the animals in here.
他比这里一半以上的动物还要野
Still won't tell me where he came from.
现在都不肯告诉我他从哪里来
But it wasrt anyplace good.
不管是哪  那绝对不是什么好地方
You got to straighten up.
你得搞搞清楚
Jimmy.
吉米
You don't want to be on this ship the rest of your life.
你不会想后半辈子都待在这条船上的
- Yes, I do.   - No, you don't, Jimmy.
- 我想的  - 不  你不想的  吉米
You got to be smart. Get yourself educated.
你要聪明一点  受点教育
Give yourself some options. Take this seriously!
给自己多点选择  你要认真对待!
I do, Mr. Hayes, I do. Look.
我有啊  赫斯先生  你看
I've been reading.
我已经在读书了
Where'd you get this?
你从哪里搞到的?
I borrowed it.
跟别人借的
(纽约市公立图书馆)
On long-term loan.
长...长期借阅
Look at this. Look, look.
看  看  看这个
"Adventures on a tramp steamer." See? Just like us.
《不定期货船上的冒险》  瞧见了吗?就跟我们一样
It's so nice to meet you, Mr. Driscoll.
见到你太高兴了  德里斯库先生
I'm actually quite familiar with your work, yes.
实际上我很熟悉你的作品  没错
Hello, Mr. Driscoll. It's so nice to meet you.
你好  德里斯库先生  很高兴见到你
Actually, I'm quite familiar with your work.
实际上我相当熟悉你的作品
I'm a huge fan.
我是你的忠实崇拜者
I've read everything you've ever written.
我读过你写的所有东西
No, too much.
太过了
Gonna have the ship's engines all over the dialogue.
整段对白里都有船的引擎噪声
Seagulls.
海鸥
Camera noise. Wind. Christ knows what else.
摄影机的噪音、风声  上帝才知道还有什么
I don't care, Mike.
我不管  麦克
You're the sound recordist. Make it work.
你是音响师  你来搞定
Ann! Come on in. Let me introduce you to the crew.
安!快进来  我来给你介绍剧组里的其他人
This is herb, the cameraman.
这是赫伯  摄影师
- Delighted to meet you, ma'am.   - Likewise.
- 很荣幸认识你  女士  - 我也一样
May I say what a lovely dress?
这裙子真是太美丽了
Oh, this old thing? I just threw it on.
这件旧衣服?我只是随便穿穿
Isn't that one of Maureers costumes?
这不是玛琳的戏服吗?
Now, what does a girl have to do around here to get some breakfast?
呃  女孩子要做点什么才能吃到早饭呢?
Lumpy, you heard the lady.
兰皮  你听到女士说的话了?
Fancy my porridge a la walnuts?
想尝尝我的麦片粥吗?里面还有核桃仁
Oh, Ann, I don't believe you've met...
噢  安  我相信你还不认识...
Ann?
安?
That's all right, Mr. Denam. I know who this is.
没关系  丹汉姆先生  我知道这位是谁
Thrilled to meet you. It's an honor to be a part of this.
见到你诚惶诚恐  非常荣幸能参与演出
Gee, thanks.
天  谢谢你
Actually, I'm quite familiar with your work.
实际上我非常熟悉你的作品
Really?
真的吗?
Yes, and what I most admire...
对  我最崇拜的是...
is the way you've captured the voice of the common people.
你捕捉普通人声音的方式
Well, that's my job.
这个嘛  我的工作就是如此
I'm sure you've heard this before, Mr. Driscoll...
我相信以前也有人这么说过  德里斯库先生...
if you don't mind me saying...
如果你不介意的话  我想说...
but you don't look at all like your photograph.
你和照片上一点也不象
- Excuse me.   - Wait a minute, Ann...
- 抱歉  - 等等  安...
he's so much younger in person. And much better-looking.
本人看起来年轻的多  也帅得多
Ann, stop. Stop right there.
安  别说了  别说了
You see, I was just afraid that you might be...
你知道  我只是担心你或许是...
one of those self-obsessed literary types.
是那种自恋的"作家"
- I'm sorry, I'm not...   - You know...
- 抱歉  我不是...  - 你知道...
the tweedy twerp with his nose in his book and his head up his a...
那种只会把头埋在书本里...
It's nice to meet you, too, Miss Darrow.
见到你也很高兴  丹劳小姐
Good Christ!
哦  上帝啊
She's standing at the railing.
她站在栏杆边
She doesn't know it yet...
她还不知道...
But they are sailing towards disaster. You got that?
但是他们正向灾难驶去  写下来了吗?
Okay, so she turns...
好  那么她转过身来...
the first mate is staggering towards her.
大副向她摇晃着走来
There's a knife sticking out of his back.
刀从他的背后直透前胸
Wait a sec. We're killing off the first mate?
等等  我们要把大副干掉?
That's assuming she knows who the first mate is.
我们首先得假设她知道大副是谁
Come on, Jack. It was an honest mistake.
少来了  杰克  这只是个真实的错误
Ann is nearsighted. It could have happened to anyone.
安是个近视眼  谁都有可能
I was joking, Carl.
我是在开玩笑  卡尔
The point is, she's horrified. She has to look away.
关键在于她非常害怕  她向别处看去
And that's when she sees it.
就在这时她看到了它
Sees what?
看到了什么?
What?
什么呀?
The island.
那个岛
We're filming on an island now? When did this happen?
我们现在要到某个岛上去拍摄?什么时候决定的事?
Jack, keep your voice down.
嘘  杰克  小点声
I don't want the crew getting spooked.
我不想要船员毛骨悚然
Why would they get spooked? What's it called?
为什么他们会毛骨悚然?岛叫什么名字?
All right. It has a local name...
好吧  那个岛有个当地的名字...
but I'm warning you, Jack, it doesn't sound good.
不过我警告你  杰克  它可不怎么好听
They call it Skull Island.
他们叫它骷髅岛
Did you get that?
你明白了吗?
What's wrong with this place?
这地方有什么问题?
There's nothing officially wrong with it.
这个地方没有什么经官方证实的问题
Because, technically, it hasn't been discovered yet.
因为从技术角度讲  它还没有被发现呢
Okay. All right.
好  好吧
So we arrive at this place.
那么我们就到了这个地方
Island.
骷髅岛
All right, everyone, from the top! And action!
好的  上面的人注意  开始!
I think this is awfully exciting! I've never been on a ship before.
实在太让人兴奋了  我以前从来没坐过船
And I've never been on one with a woman before.
我以前从没坐过有女人的船
I guess you don't think much of women on ships, do you?
我想你们在船上不太会想女人  对吗?
No, they're a nuisance.
是啊  他们太麻烦了
Well, I'll try not to be.
我会尽量不给你们添麻烦的
Just being around is trouble.
你在我们周围就已经是麻烦了
Cut!
停!
It's great.
非常好
Bruce, wonderful performance. You can relax for 10 minutes.
布鲁斯  演得非常好  你可以放松10分钟
That was very natural. I felt moved.
表演非常自然  我都被感动了
What do you think, Driscoll? Dialogue's got some flow now, huh?
你觉得怎么样  德里斯库?对白现在不那么生硬了  对吧?
It was pure effluence.
真是完全的感情流露啊
I beefed up the banter.
我加了点善意的嘲弄而已
Try to resist that impulse.
还是克制这种冲动吧
It's just a little bit of humor, bud.
只是一点幽默感罢了  朋友
What are you, a Bolshevik or something?
你是什么?布尔什维克吗?
Actors.
演员哪
Travel the world, but all they ever see is a mirror.
踏遍整个世界  却只能看到一面镜子
Good legs.
好漂亮的腿
Sea legs. Well, you know, sea legs.
是晕船的意思 呃  你知道  晕船
Yeah.
耶
Not that you don't have good legs. Just making conversation.
不是说你没有漂亮的腿  只是不小心说出来了
Jesus. Miss Darrow!
上帝啊  丹劳小姐!
About the scene today with you and Bruce...
今天你和布鲁斯的那场戏...
I know it wasrt what you wrote...
我知道你不是那么写的...
but Mr. Baxter felt very strongly that when a man likes a woman...
可巴克斯特先生强烈地认为如果一个男人喜欢一个女人
he must ignore her.
那么他一定要忽视她的存在
And if things turn really hostile, then...
如果敌意真的变得很深...
No?
不会吗?
Interesting theory.
这是个有趣的理论
I know. I should have...
我知道  我应该...
It wasrt what I had intended, but...
这并非我本意  不过...
I'm sorry. I was...
抱歉  我...
And you made it your own.
你做了自己的诠释
I was nervous.
我当时好紧张
- It was funny, actually.   - You were funny.
- 当时很滑稽  实际上  - 你当时是很滑稽
Please don't say another word. Good night.
拜托别再说下去了  晚安
Miss Darrow.
丹劳小姐
You don't have to be nervous.
你不用紧张
Thank you.
谢谢你
Let's take it...
我们再...
Would you please... We're trying to shoot a scene.
你可不可以... 我们这儿正在拍  谢谢
- Okay.   - Thank you.
- 好的  - 多谢
Okay, again.
好的  再来
We're close. Turn southwest.
我们快到了  转向西南
There's no land southwest for thousands of miles.
西南方向上千英里内都没有陆地
It takes us way outside the shipping lanes.
我们离正常航线越来越远
I won't sail blind in these waters.
我不能摸黑在这片水域行驶
I'll make it won'th your while.
我会补偿你的
There's nothing out there.
那里什么也没有
Well, then you've nothing to lose.
那样的话  你也不会失去什么
If someone were to tell you this ship was headed for Singapore...
如果有人对你说  这条船没有驶向新加坡...
what would you say?
你会怎么说?
I would say they're full of it, Mr. Hayes.
我会说千真万确  赫斯先生
Well, we turned southwest last night.
昨天晚上我们转向西南了
Gentlemen, please.
先生们  拜托
- We're not looking for trouble.   - No.
- 我们不想找麻烦  - 不
You're looking for something else.
你们在找别的什么东西
Yes, we are.
对  你说得对
We're going to find Skull Island.
我们要找到骷髅岛
Find it, film it, and show it to the world.
找到它  拍摄下来展示给整个世界
For 25 cents, you get to see the last blank space on the map.
只要花25美分  你就可以看到地图上最后的空白
I wouldn't be so sure of that.
我不知道那是不是好事
What do you mean?
你什么意思?
Seven years ago, me and Mr. Hayes were working our passage...
七年前我和赫斯先生一起工作在...
on a Norwegian bark.
一艘挪威帆船上
We picked up a castaway. We found him in the water.
我们从水中救起了一个海难的幸存者
He'd been drifting for days.
他已经漂了很多天了
His ship had run aground on an island way west of Sumatra.
他们的船在一个岛上搁浅了  在苏门答腊以西很远的地方
An island hidden in fog.
一座隐藏在迷雾中的岛
He spoke of a huge wall...
他说起一道巨大的城墙...
built so long ago...
建于久远的年代...
no one knew who'd made it.
没有人知道是谁建造了它
A wall 100 foot high...
墙高100英尺...
as strong today as it was ages ago.
现在仍然和建成时一样坚固
Why'd they build the wall?
他们为什么要建一道墙呢?
Well, the castaway, he spoke of a creature...
那个幸存者  他说起一个生物...
neither beast nor man...
既非野兽  也非人类...
but something monstrous, living behind that wall.
但的确有可怕的生物  就活在那座墙后
A lion or a tiger.
一头老虎或者狮子?
A man-eater. That's how all these stories start.
或者是吃人的家伙?所有故事都是这么开始的
What else did he say?
他还说什么了?
Nothing.
什么也没说
We found him the next morning. He'd stuck a knife through his heart.
第二天早晨我们发现他的心脏上插了一把刀
Mmm-hmm.
呣
Sorry, fellows. You'll have to do better than that.
抱歉  伙计们  编故事编好点
Monsters belong in B movies.
怪兽  只在B级电影里才出现
If you find this place...
如果你找到这个地方...
if you go ashore with your friends and your cameras...
如果你和你的朋友们还有你们的摄像机一起上岸的话...
you won't come back.
你们就永远也回不来了
Just as long as you understand that.
只是想要你们明白这一点
(迷雾)
How long do you expect us to stay out here?
你认为我们会在这里待多长时间?
You're writing a stage comedy?
你在写一出舞台喜剧?
I'm writing it for you.
我为你而写的
Why would you do that?
你为什么要这么做?
- Why would I write a play for you?   - Yes.
- 为什么我要为你写一出戏?  - 是啊
Isn't it obvious?
这还不明显吗?
Not to me.
对我来说不是
Well...
这个嘛...
it's in the subtext.
在潜台词里已经说明了
I guess I must have missed it.
那我一定是没看到
It's not about words.
不是言语上的
Message for you, Captain.
给你的  船长
What's going on?
出什么事情了?
Hayes, why are we changing course?
赫斯  我们为什么要改变航向?
- Englehorn, you can't just...   - Outside.
- 安格霍恩  你不能...  - 外面说!
There's a warrant out for your arrest.
你的逮捕证已经下发了
Did you know that?
这个你知道吗?
I've been ordered to divert to Rangoon.
我已经下命令转驶向仰光了
Another week. I haven't got a film yet.
再给我一个星期  我的电影还没有拍成
Please. I have risked everything I have on this.
求求你  我把我的一切都押上了
No, Denam. You risked everything I have.
不  丹汉姆  你把我的一切都押上了
What do you want?
你想要什么?
Tell me what you want. I'll give you anything.
告诉我你想要什么?我什么都可以给你
I want you off my ship.
我想要你下船
Set a course for Rangoon, Mr. Hayes.
设定到仰光的航向  赫斯先生
I'm finished.
我完蛋了
It's over for me, Jack.
对我来说结束了  杰克
How'd you think this would end, Carl?
你认为会有怎样的结局呢  卡尔?
Check our position. Use the stars.
检查一下我们的位置  用星星
There are no stars, Captain.
天上没有星星  船长
What is that?
这是什么?
- What?   - That.
- 什么东西?  - 这个
That right there.
这个  就在这儿
I don't know. What is it? A coffee stain?
不知道  是什么?也许是咖啡渍吧
Station the forward lookout and get me the depth by lead line.
守好前方观望台  告诉我测深索的深度
Aye, Captain.
是  船长
30 fathoms, no bottom!
30英寻  没见底!
Reduce speed, steerage way only.
减速  只用低速
Dead slow ahead, both.
双机低速前进
You should stop the ship.
你应该停船
15 degrees port.
左舵15度
We're getting out of here, Mr. Hayes.
赫斯先生  我们会走出去的
We'll find clear conditions.
我们会找到没有雾的区域的
We have seabed!
测到海底了!
25 fathoms!
25英寻!
We're shallowing!
水越来越浅了!
20 degrees starboard!
右舵20度!
Captain, you don't know where the hell you're going!
船长  你根本不知道你正驶向哪里!
Get me another reading!
再去读个深度!
Another reading!
再读一次深度!
22 fathoms!
22英寻!
- Douse the lights.   - Aye, Captain.
- 把灯关掉  - 是  船长
10 fathoms!
10英寻!
Wall! There's a wall ahead!
城墙!正前方有堵墙!
Stop engines!
关闭发动机!
Give me some power! Half astern both.
给我点动力!半速前进!
Half astern both, Captain!
半速前进  船长!
Rocks!
礁石!
Rocks to starboard, Captain!
右舷有礁石  船长!
To port! Rocks everywhere!
左舷也有礁石!到处都是礁石!
Take the wheel, hayes.
你来掌舵  赫斯
Hang on!
抓住!
Full ahead!
全速前进!
Rocks to port, Captain!
左舷有礁石  船长!
- Turn, Captain!   - Starboard, starboard!
- 躲过了  船长  - 右弦!右弦!
Ah!
啊!
Shore up that breach!
把这个洞堵上!
Get me more men down here now! Come on, move, move!
给我找更多人下来!来吧  快点  快!
- Hayes!   - She's taken a pounding!
- 赫斯!  - 船被狠狠撞了一下!
What about the prop?
推进器怎么样?
The shaft's not bent, as far as we can tell.
如我们现在所知  主轴没弯
But she struck hard against the rock!
我们卡在礁石上了!
Captain!
船长!
Better come up quick!
你最好快点上来!
Right there!
就在那儿!
Want me to bring them back?
你想让我带他们回来吗?
I don't give a damn about Carl Denam.
卡尔·丹汉姆关我屁事
I want this ship fixed and ready to float on the next high tide!
下次涨潮之前要把这条船修好!
Come on, move it.
快点  加油干!
We're leaving, Mr. Hayes.
我们要走了  赫斯先生
Can you believe this, Jack?
你能相信吗  杰克?
We've got our picture.
我们的电影拍成了
Why does Marlow keep going up the river?
为什么马洛非要逆流而上呢?
Why doesn't he turn back?
他为什么不回头?
There's a part of him that wants to, Jimmy.
有一个"他"想要那么做  吉米
A part deep inside himself that sounds a warning.
他心底有个声音在发出警告
But there's another part...
可是那另一个"他"...
that needs to know.
需要去探索个究竟
To defeat the thing which makes him afraid.
好打败那让他恐惧的东西
"We could not understand because we were too far...
"我们过去无法理解  因为我们身在遥远的彼方...
and could not renenber...
我们也早已淡忘...
because we were traveling in the night of first ages...
因为那旅行是穿过史前时代的长夜...
of those ages that are gone...
而那时代早已远去...
leaving hardly a sign, and no nenories.
了无踪迹  也没有回忆
We are accustoned to look...
我们已经司空见惯了...
upon the shackled forn of a conquered nonster...
带着沉重枷锁的被征服的巨兽...
but there...
但在那里...
there you could look at a thing nonstrous and free."
在那里你会见到一个凶残并且无拘无束的它"
It's not an adventure story...
这不是个冒险故事...
is it, Mr. Hayes?
对吗  赫斯先生?
No, Jimmy.
对  吉米
It's not.
不是
- It's deserted.   - Of course it's deserted.
- 这是个荒废了的地方  - 这当然是个被荒废的地方
Use your eyes, Preston. The place is a ruin.
睁开眼睛看看  普雷斯顿  这地方就是个废墟
Nobody's lived here for hundreds of years.
成百上千年没有人住过了
Mr. Denam, I think we should go back.
丹汉姆先生  我想我们该回去了
I will handle this.
这个我来处理
(牛奶巧克力)
Look. Chocolate.
看  巧克力
You like chocolate?
你喜欢巧克力吗?
It's good to eat.
很好吃的
You want?
想要吗?
Take it.
拿着吧
Here, put it in your hand and take it.
这里  拿在手里吧  拿着
For God's sakes, Denam, leave the native alone.
看在上帝的份上  丹汉姆  别跟这些土著纠缠了
She doesn't want the chocolate.
她不想要你的巧克力
Aah!
啊!
All right!
没事的!
Just a bunch of women and old folks!
只是女人和老人!
They're harmless!
不会有危险的!
Ann!
安!
Jack.
杰克!
Seen enough?
这下开眼了吧
Lighten the ship!
给船减轻重量!
Anything that's not bolted down goes overboard!
不是必需的东西都扔下去!
Just heave it!
举起来!
We got away.
我们逃出来了
We gotta be grateful for that, gentlemen.
我们得心存感激  先生们
What about Mike? He didn't get away! He's still there!
那麦克呢?他可没逃出来  他现在都还在那儿呢!
Mike died doing what he believed in! He didn't die for nothing.
麦克死得其所!他的死不是没有价值的
And I'll tell you something else. I'm gonna finish this film for Mike!
我再告诉你一件事  我会为了麦克把这部电影拍完的!
I'll finish it...
我会把它拍完的...
and I'll donate the proceeds...
我还要把影片的收益捐给...
to his wife and kids.
他的妻子和孩子
Because that man is a hero, and he deserves nothing less.
因为那人是个英雄  他应该得到这样的荣誉
Hear, hear!
听啊  听!
Chuck everything except for the potatoes!
除了土豆  把能扔的都扔掉
- What's wrong now?   - Excuse me, Shakespeare.
- 这到底是怎么了?  - 抱歉  莎士比亚
Come on, men! Come on, hurry!
来吧  老兄  来吧  快点
Drop those spare cables overboard! Go on, just chuck it!
把那些多余的缆绳扔掉!快啊  扔掉!
- Where's Ann?   - What?
- 安在哪里?  - 什么?
Where's Ann?
安在哪里?
Ann!
安!
She's free!
脱离困境了!
Full ahead, both engines!
双机全速前进!
Ann!
安!
No! Stop! Turn back!
不!停船!回去!
Stop!
停船!
We have to turn back.
我们必须掉头
They've taken Ann.
他们抢走了安
Kong! Kong! Kong!
刚!刚!刚!
All hands going ashore! Report to stations!
全体人员准备上岸!报告位置!
Jump to it! Jump to it, gentlemen!
快点  快点  先生们!
We're doing it, Mr. Hayes!
我们正在做  赫斯先生!
Come on, move it!
来吧  快点!
Pull harder!
用力划!
Row! Row!
划啊!划啊!
Come on!
加油!
Kong.
刚
Spread out! Find her!
散开来  找到她!
Miss Darrow!
丹劳小姐!
- Check up there, Jimmy!   - Everybody stay together!
- 去那边找  吉米!  - 所有人不要走散了!
Ann!
安!
She's here somewhere!
她应该就在附近!
What in God's name was that?
上帝啊  那是什么东西?
Behind the wall!
在城墙后面!
城墙后面!
She's gone!
她不见了!
Carl, what is it?
卡尔  怎么了?
You saw something.
你见到什么了?
You can take hayes and 15 others.
赫斯带15个人跟你们去
I'll put a guard on the gate until you return.
我派人守卫城门  直到你们回来
The rest of you stay with the ship.
其他人在船上等
Choy!
老崔!
Not you, Jimmy.
吉米  你不去
Come on, Mr. Hayes. Look at them.
不要这样  赫斯先生  看看他们
None of them knows which way to point a gun.
没人会用枪
Stay here.
你呆在这里
- Miss Darrow needs me!   - No!
- 丹劳小姐需要我!  - 不!
Bring the tripod and all of the film stock.
带上三角架跟其他拍摄设备
You wanna go with the 6-inch lens?
你要六寸长焦镜头吗?
The wide-angle will do just fine.
普通广角镜足够了
You got guns. You got food. You got the ammo.
你们有枪、有食物、有弹药
And you got 24 hours!
给你们24小时!
24 hours?
24小时啊
This time tomorrow, we haul anchor.
明天这个时候我们启锚
Miss Darrow!
丹劳小姐!
Ann!
安!
Miss Darrow!
丹劳小姐!
What is it?
那是什么?
Fire!
开火!
Cut it out.
阻止它
Hold your fire.
停火
Hold your fire!
停火!
Stay down, damn it. Stay down.
趴下  妈的  趴下
Come on. Come on. Come on.
来啊  来啊
Good shooting, Mr. Hayes.
打的好  赫斯先生
Arert these things supposed to be extinct?
这些东西不是绝种了么?
They are now.
他们现在是了
What the hell kind of a place is this?
这他妈到底是什么地方?
Miss Darrow!
丹劳小姐!
Ann!
安!
No!
不!
- Ann!   - Miss Darrow!
- 安!  - 丹劳小姐!
Ann!
安!
Christ, it's a bleeding boneyard!
好家伙  这里好像流着血的坟场
They've been ripped limb from limb.
他们都被分肢了
Ann! Ann!
安!安!
Just keep walking, Mr. Hayes. Pretend you didn't see me.
赫斯先生  继续走就是了  当没看见我
- Jesus, Jimmy. Hey,   - I need that!
- 耶稣基督啊  吉米  - 我需要那把枪
I'm not giving you a gun!
我不会给你枪的
You were younger than me when they gave you one!
他们发枪给你的时候比我还小!
I was in the Army. I was trained. I had a drill sergeant.
我那是在陆军里  有教练士官教我
I wanna help bring her back.
我想帮忙找她回来
Don't make me regret it.
不要让我后悔
Conserve your ammunition!
节省弹药
I'm knackered.
我都累死了
- I gotta have a breather.   - Great idea.
- 我不能呼吸了  - 我需要人工呼吸
Fellows, we don't have time for this.
伙计们  没时间了
We've lost too much ground already. Come on, get up!
我们已经延误了  起来吧!
They're not about to quit on you. Cut them some slack.
他们需要休息  放松一下.
All right, you got five minutes!
你们可以休息5分钟
Everybody stay in sight.
所有人都要待在我的视线以内
Over here. I'm gonna get a wide shot of the valley.
到这边来 我要给峡谷拍一个广角
Bloody Nora!
血腥诺拉!
Is that what took Miss Darrow?
就是这东西抓走了丹劳小姐?
There's only one creature capable of leaving a footprint that size.
只有一种生物可以留下这么大的脚印
The abominable snowman.
恐怖的雪人
Yeah, a snowman. We dead meat.
是啊  雪人  我们是刀板上的鱼肉了
It's got to be what, 20, 25 feet?
那东西得多大  20  25英尺高?
Carl saw it.
卡尔看到过
Let's ask him.
我们问问他
Denam!
丹汉姆!
Where'd he go?
他跑哪里去了?
Walk forward, Bruce.
走过去  布鲁斯
- What?   - You're the star of this picture.
- 什么?  - 你是片子主角
Get into character and head toward the animals.
进入角色  走向那群动物
What the hell kind of a place is this?
这里到底是他妈的什么地方啊
Are you sure about this, Denam?
你确定这能行吗  丹汉姆?
Don't we have a stand-in for this type of thing?
这种事没替身的吗?
I need you in the shot, or people will say they're fake.
我要你在镜头里  不然别人说这是假的
Nobody's gonna think these are fake.
没人会说这是假的
You're making them nervous. No sudden movements.
你让它们紧张了  别突然乱动
I'm not moving.
我没动
Mother of God.
上帝他妈啊
What's this?
怎么回事?
What is it? What is it? Where's Carl?
怎么了  怎么了?卡尔在哪?
Carl? He's up there, filming.
卡尔?他...他在那边  拍电影
Bugger this!
小心!
Run, Jack!
跑啊  杰克!
Holy Christ. Go, Jimmy, run!
耶稣基督啊  快走  吉米  跑啊!
Run, run, run!
跑  跑  跑啊!
- Let go!   - I'm not leaving the camera!
- 你放手  - 我不会丢下摄影机的
Let go, you idiot!
快放手  你个笨蛋
Carl, run!
卡尔  快跑
Look out!
趴下
看着点!
Coming through!
过来了!
No!
不!
Come on.
来啊!
Carl! Carl!
卡尔!卡尔!
Get up! Come on. Come on.
起来!快走  快走
Mr. Denam! Mr. Denam!
丹汉姆先生!丹汉姆先生!
Herb! Herb, come on!
赫伯  赫伯!快点!
Take the tripod!
抓住三角架!
Come on!
来啊!
I'm pulling you up! Hold on to your end!
我把你拉上来  抓紧了支脚
Go!
走吧!
No, I'm not going anywhere without you!
不  没你我哪儿也不去
- You gotta leave me!   - Shut up and hold on!
- 你应该离开我  - 闭嘴  抓住了
Jimmy, do a head count.
吉米  算算人头数
I want to know how many are injured and how bad.
我想知道有多少人受了伤  伤势如何
Injured?
受伤?
Four of us are dead!
我们死了4个人!
It's not your fault.
这不是你的错
What happened to herb is no one's fault.
发生在赫伯身上的事  不是谁的错
You're absolutely right, Preston.
你说的很对  普雷斯顿
And I'll tell you something else.
我再告诉你一件事情
Herbert didn't die for nothing.
赫伯没有无谓的死去
He died for what he believed in, and I'm gonna honor that.
他死得其所  我要纪念他
He died believing there was still some mystery left in this world.
他死是因为相信世界上还有些奥秘
And we could all have a piece of it...
而我们大家都有可能了解到其中的一部分...
for the price of an admission ticket.
只消一张门票的价钱
God damn it, Preston, we're gonna finish this film for herb.
该死的  普雷斯顿  我们要为赫伯完成这部片子
We'll finish it...
我们要完成它...
and donate the proceeds to his wife and kids.
把收益捐给他的妻子和孩子
Come on, guys. We need more rope.
伙计们  我们还需要更多的绳子
All right, we gotta get back to the ship.
好吧  我们得回去了
Englehorn sails in nine hours.
安格霍恩会在9小时后开船
So? We gotta find Miss Darrow.
那又怎样?我们要找到丹劳小姐
Hey, do you hear me? We're gonna be stranded here.
嘿!你在听我讲吗?我们会被困在这里的
Miss Darrow was a great gal, no question.
听着  伙计们  丹劳小姐是好姑娘  毫无疑问
And she was a wonderful person.
她是很好的人
It's a terrible loss and we're all gonna miss her.
她的死是可怕的损失  我们都会想念她的
I always knew you were nothing like the tough guy you play on screen.
我就知道你不是银幕上所演的那种硬汉形象
I just never figured you for a coward.
我只是没想到你居然是个懦夫
Hey, pal! Hey, wake up.
嘿  伙计  嘿  醒醒吧
Heroes don't look like me, not in the real world.
真实生活里的英雄不像我这样
In the real world, they got bad teeth, a bald spot, and a beer gut.
真实生活里他们都有坏牙跟啤酒肚
I'm just an actor with a gun, who's lost his motivation.
我只是个拿枪的演员  并且失去了动力
Be seeing you.
回头见
Anyone else?
还有谁吗?
- Well, see you.   - Come on.
- 好吧  回见  - 别...
No!
不!
I said no!
我说了  不!
That's all there is. There isn't any more.
到此为止  没有了
Get them off the boat. Get them off the boat.
赶他们下船!赶他们下船!
Keep paddling.
继续划啊!
What the hell was that?
到底是什么东西?
Come on. Get them out of there!
来啊  把他们赶跑!
Preston!
普雷斯顿!
Give me your hand.
给我你的手
Jack!
杰克!
Choy! Help!
老崔!救命!
Swim, you filthy bugger.
游啊  你个脏虫子!
Choy!
老崔!
Stay with him.
跟着他
Swim to shore as fast as you can!
尽快游到河岸去!
Hold on. Preston!
坚持住  普雷斯顿!
Whatever happens, don't let go of the camera!
不管发生什么  别丢了摄像机!
Don't let go of the camera!
别丢了摄像机!
Come on, get up out of that water.
来吧  起来  离开水
Get up!
起来!
Come on, come on.
来啊  来啊!
Preston. Preston.
普雷斯顿  普雷斯顿
It's working.
还能用
Did you get that, did you?
你有拍到是吧?
No!
不!
No.
What is it?
怎么了?
Mr. Hayes?
赫斯先生?
If anything happens, I want you to run.
如果有什么不测  我希望你赶快跑
You understand?
明白了?
I'm not a coward. I ain't gonna run.
我不是懦夫  我才不会跑呢
It's not about being brave, Jimmy.
这并非什么勇敢  吉米
Go back!
回去!
Back across the log!
回去木桥那边!
- I ain't gonna run!   - Get Jimmy out of here!
- 我不能就这么跑掉!  - 把吉米带走!
- No!   - Get back! Get back!
- 不!  - 后退!后退!
- No! No!   - Stay back.
- 不!不!  - 呆着别动
No!
不!
Look at me.
看着我
- Let him go!   - You got to run, Jimmy.
- 放他走!  - 你要跑了  吉米
Do as I say.
按我说的做
Go with Jack.
跟杰克一起走
Run!
跑啊!
- No!   - Shoot him!
- 不!  - 开枪射他!
No!
不!
Here! Over here!
这里  在这边!
Hold on! Hold on!
坚持住!坚持!
Lumpy! Help me!
兰皮!救我!
Bloody hell, Choy!
他妈的地狱  老崔!
No!
不!
Oh, my!
哦  我的神啊!
Wait!
等等我
Carl.
卡尔
Jimmy. Jimmy.
吉米!吉米!
Jimmy.
吉米!
You all right?
你还好吗?
No.
不
Get off! Get it off!
下去  下去!
Get off!
下去!
Get it off!
Kill it!
杀了它!
Stop moving!
别动
Get it off my face!
把它从我脸上弄走
- Stay still.   - I am standing still.
- 站着别动  - 我没动
- Hold on.   - Be careful!
- 等一下  - 小心!
Don't move! Stay away from the walls!
别动  离崖壁远点
Coming through!
脱险了!
Get out of there now! Climb!
现在离开那儿!往上爬!
Nobody get in my way.
没人能挡我的道
Come on, Jimmy. Let's go.
来吧  吉米  我们走
Get up the rope. Let's go. Hurry up.
爬上绳子  快
Jimmy, let's go.
吉米  我们走了
Come on. Okay.
快来啊  好的
Go.
走
Just as you go down...
就在你下沉...
for the third and final time...
到第三也是最后一次时...
as your head disappears beneath the waves...
就在你的头淹没在浪头下...
and your lungs fill with water...
你的肺也充满了水...
do you know what happens in those last precious seconds before you drown?
在你淹死前
你知道那仅存的珍贵的几秒钟都发生了什么嘛?
Come on, buddy. Get up the rope. Come on. Get out of here. Come on.
来吧  兄弟  爬上绳子去  来啊  离开这  来吧
Your whole life passes before your eyes.
你的整个人生会在眼前一幌而过
And if you've lived as a true American...
而如果你活得像个真正的美国人...
you get to watch it all in color.
你会看到那是有色彩的
Oh, and you will.
哦  你会的
Now, why don't you climb up the rope, huh? Come on.
现在  你干吗不爬上绳子呢?来吧
Come on, Driscoll. Let's go.
来吧  德里斯库  我们走
It's beautiful.
真美丽
Beautiful.
美丽
There.
那边
Thank God.
感谢上帝
Don't thank God. Thank Mr. Baxter.
别谢上帝  要谢巴克斯特先生
He insisted on a rescue mission.
他坚持要救你们
Me? I knew you'd be okay.
我?我就知道你不会有事
That's the thing about cockroaches.
这就是蟑螂的特点
No matter how many times you flush them down the toilet...
不管你把它们从厕所里冲走多少次...
they always crawl back up the bowl.
它们总是爬回到碗里来
Hey, buddy? I'm out of the bowl.
嘿  伙计  我从碗里出来了
I'm dryir off my wings and trekkir across the lid.
我在晾干我的翅膀  正沿着碗盖散步呢
Driscoll!
德里斯库!
Don't be a fool! Give it up. It's useless!
别犯傻!放弃吧  没用的!
She's dead.
她死了
She's not dead.
她没死
Jack's gonna bring her back...
杰克会救她回来...
and the ape will be hard on his heels.
那猩猩会紧追不放的
We can still come out of this thing okay.
我们还有机会翻本  好吧?
More than okay.
还有的赚
Think about it.
想想吧
You got a boat full of chloroform we could put to good use.
你有一整船的氯仿可用
You wanna trap the ape?
你想抓那猩猩
I don't think so.
我可不这么想
Isn't that what you do? Live animal capture?
这不是你拿手的吗  活捉动物
I heard you were the best.
我听说你是最好的
Jack!
杰克!
Look after yourself!
照顾好你自己!
Keep the gate open, will you?
把城门开着  可以吗?
Sure thing, buddy.
没问题  伙计
Good luck!
祝你好运!
I'm sorry.
对不起
Ann.
安
Jack!
杰克!
Run!
快跑!
Jack, Jack!
杰克  杰克!
Jack.
杰克
Ann, it's okay.
安  没事的
Ann, let's go. Let's go. Come on!
安  我们走  我们走  来吧!
Let's go. Come on.
我们要走了  来吧
Come on!
来啊!
Carl!
卡尔!
Please! Somebody help us!
有人吗  请帮帮我们!
They've gone.
他们走了
Carl. Christ.
卡尔  上帝啊!
Carl!
卡尔!
Drop the bridge. Do it now, for Christ's sake!
把吊桥放下  现在就放  看在上帝份儿上!
Not yet.
还不是时候
Wait.
等着
Wait!
等着!
Come on!
来啊!
Now! Throw them!
就现在!扔钩子啊!
Throw!
扔啊!
No!
不要!
Hold him!
抓住他
Are you out of your mind?
你疯了吗?
- Stop!   - Hold the line!
- 住手!  - 抓住绳子
Keep him down!
把他压住!
Heave!
拉啊!
Please!
求你了!
No! Stop!
不要!停手!
Jack.
杰克
- No.   - Get her out of...
- 住手  - 把她带走...
- They'll kill him!   - There's nothing we can do.
- 他们会杀了他的!  - 我们什么也做不了
- No!   - Get her out of his sight!
- 不!  - 把她带出它的视线!
- It's too late.   - Throw it!
- 太迟了  - 扔啊!
Look out!
留神啊!
Let go of me.
放开我
We gotta go. Come on.
我们得走了  来吧
- Come on.   - Stop it.
- 来吧  - 住手
Leave me alone!
放开我!
Ann, please come on.
安  求你  走吧
- Kill it!   - No. No!
- 打死它!  - 不要!不!
It's over, you goddamn lunatic!
结束了  你个疯子
All of you, run!
所有人  逃命!
Come on. Come on!
加油  加油!
Move it! Move it!
跑啊!跑啊!
Come on, come on!
快  快点!
- Stay there!   - It's me he wants!
- 呆在那!  - 他要的是我!
- Please stop this!   - Move! Hold onto her!
- 求你制止这一切!  - 快走  拦住她!
Ann, go. Please, I can stop this!
安  走吧  求你  我可以制止他!
No! Ann, stay there!
不!安  呆在哪儿!
Get it out!
离开这儿!
Get the hell out of here!
赶快他妈的离开这儿!
- Come on!   - Jimmy, don't be crazy! Come on.
- 来吧!  - 吉米  别犯傻了!来吧
Don't be crazy.
别犯傻了
Let me go!
让我走!
Cast off!
起锚!
Come on, Carl!
来啊  卡尔!
- Row!   - Wait.
- 划船  - 等等
Row, God damn it!
划船  他妈的!
Go back.
回去
Jimmy, no!
吉米  不!
No!
不!
No! Don't! Leave him alone!
不!别开枪!放他条生路!
Hide out in the back!
躲在后面!
- Wait!   - No!
- 等一下!  - 不!
No! No! Please don't!
不!求你了!不要!
The whole world will pay to see this.
全世界都会要付钱看它
We're millionaires, boys!
我们是百万富翁了  弟兄们!
I'll share it with all of you!
我会跟你们所有人共享的!
In a few months his name will be up in lights on Broadway!
几个月之内  它的名字会在百老汇的灯光里出现
Kong! The Eighth Wonder of the World!
金刚!世界第八大奇迹!
(金刚 世界第八大奇迹)
(金刚 卡尔·丹汉姆的巨型怪兽)
(看安妮·丹劳被奉献给"野兽")
(售完)
What can I say? What can I say?
我能说什么?我能说什么?
Any comments, Mr. Denam?
有什么想法  先生?
The Mayor, thank you.
市长大人  谢谢你
Ready.
准备好
What am I?
我是谁?
Thank you very much.
非常感谢你
Get used to it.
习惯了就好
Listen, it's great to see you. Ready?
非常高兴见到你  你准备好了吗?
I'm really appreciating that...
谢谢你的关心...
Look at you! I remember you.
看看你!我记得你
- You're a lucky guy, Denam.   - Am I a lucky guy?
- 你真是好运气  丹汉姆先生  - 可不是好运吗?
Maybe you're the lucky guy.
或许你就是个幸运儿
Carl!
卡尔!
Zelman! I told them.
索尔曼!我跟你说了!
I know you did and I appreciate it.
我知道你会来的  我真的很喜欢
Let's get a shot of this.
让我们来照相
Come on.
来吧
Big smile. Yeah! That's great!
大笑一下 耶!这真是太棒了!
Look at yourself. Look at what you've becone.
看看你自己  看看你成了什么样
- No woman is won'th this.   - This woman is won'th it.
- 没有女人值得你这样  - 这个女人值得
I don't care what it takes, I gotta win her back.
我不管什么代价  一定要赢得她
Oh, really?
哦  真的吗?
She's not gonna buy this for a second.
她才不会买这个呢
Shut up and hand me the grapefruit!
闭嘴  把那个葡萄柚给我
- You're writing a conedy?   - Yes, I an.
- 你在写一部喜剧?  - 没错
I'm writing it for you.
是为你写的
Why would you do that?
你为什么要这么做?
Why would I write a play for you?
为什么我要为你写一出戏?
Isn't it obvious?
这还不明显吗?
Oh, I'm sorry.
哦  对不起
I couldn't help but overhear.
我无意间听到的
So, he took me to this fancy French restaurant...
于是  他领我去了那豪华法国餐馆...
and halfway through the hors d'oeuvres, he clutches my hand.
吃饭当间  他抓住了我的手
And that's when he told you how he felt?
就是他向你表白的时候了吧  他感觉怎样?
- No. He never said it.   - He never said it?
- 不  他一直没说  - 他一直没说吗?
He probably thought he didn't need to say it.
他大概以为不用说了吧
Well, then how does she know that it's real?
那她怎么知道这就是认真的呢?
- He said it was not about the words.   - Oh, please!
- 他说不必用言语  - 有没有搞错
If you feel it, you say it. It's really very simple.
心里有感动  就说出来  其实很简单的
He said we'd talk about it later. Only there was no later.
他说以后再说  只是  不会有以后了
It never happened.
从来没有说出口过
That's how it ended.
就这么结束了
He just let you walk away? He didn't try to save it?
他让你就这么走了?他没有试图挽留?
I honestly believed things might actually work out...
老实说  我觉得事情或许真的有结果了...
which was really very...
那就是真的很...
foolish.
愚蠢
Men. Oh, they'll give you the world...
男人哪  哦  他会给女人整个世界...
but they let the one thing that truly matters...
却让最重要的事情...
slip through their fingers.
溜过指尖
Typical.
太常见了
They're so busy being brave,
他们太忙于展示他们的勇敢
they forget to use their brains.
以至于忘了用用他们的脑子
Romance. Who needs it?
浪漫  谁需要?
Thank you.
谢谢
Ladies and gentlemen...
女士们  先生们...
I'm here to tell you a very strange story.
我来这里是要给你们讲述一个奇异的故事
The story of our adventure...
一个有关我们的历险的故事...
in which 17 of our party suffered horrible deaths...
17名探险队员惨死...
their lives lost...
他们献出了自己的生命...
in pursuit of a savage beast...
去追寻一只野兽...
a monstrous aberration of nature.
一只大自然创造的狂大怪物
But even the meanest brute can be tamed.
但即使是最难对付的畜生也会被驯服
Yes, ladies and gentlemen, as you will see...
是的  女士们先生们  你们将要看到...
the beast was no match...
野兽并不能抵挡...
for the charms of a girl.
一个女孩的魅力
A girl from New York...
一个来自纽约的女孩...
Who melted his heart...
她融化了他的心...
bringing to mind that old Arabian proverb...
这让我们想起古老的阿拉伯诗句
"And lo, the beast looked upon the face of beauty...
"看啊  野兽端详着美女的面庞...
and beauty stayed his hand.
而美女静立于他的掌中
And from that day forward, he was as one dead."
从那天开始  他便如行尸一般了"
And now, ladies and gentlemen, I'm going to show you...
现在女士们先生们  我要向你们展示...
the greatest thing your eyes have ever beheld.
你们所见过的最伟大的事物
He was a king in the world he knew, but he comes to you now a captive.
他是世界之王  他知道  但它在你们面前则是囚犯
Ladies and gentlemen...
女士们先生们...
I give you Kong, The Eighth Wonder of the World!
我向你们推出  金刚  世界第八奇迹!
Don't be alarmed. It's perfectly safe.
不必惊惶  这是绝对安全的
These chains are made of chrome steel!
这些锁链是用铬钢做的!
Observe, if you will...
敬请观看...
I am touching the beast.
我手碰到野兽了
I am actually laying my hand on the 25-foot gorilla.
我的手放在25英尺高的大猩猩身上
Crank 'em up, fellas.
伙计们  把它拉起来
And now, we have in the auditorium tonight...
今晚在观众席中...
a surprise guest.
有一位神秘嘉宾
The real-life hero of this story.
故事里的真正英雄
The man who hunted down the mighty Kong!
追猎到强大金刚的人!
The man who risked all to win the freedom of a helpless female.
冒着生命危险去解救身处绝境的女性的人
A big hand for Mr. Bruce Baxter!
为布鲁斯·巴克斯特先生鼓掌
Thank you. Thank you.
谢谢!谢谢!
Thank you.
谢谢!
He was right.
他说得对
About there still being some mystery left in this world...
关于世界上仍有很多奥秘...
and we can all have a piece of it...
我们大家都可以了解到其中的一部分...
for the price of an admission ticket.
只消一张门票的价钱
That's the thing you come to learn about Carl.
你现在了解卡尔了吧
His unfailing ability to destroy the things he loves.
他那无穷无尽破坏他钟爱的事物的能力
Please remain calm, ladies and gentlemen...
女士们先生们  请保持镇定...
for we now come to the climax of this savage ritual.
现在是这原始的祭祀仪式的高潮
The sacrifice of a beautiful young girl.
供奉一位年轻美丽的女孩!
Behold her terror as she is offered up to the mighty Kong!
她被献给强大的金刚
A big hand, folks, for the bravest girl I've ever met!
请为我所见  最勇敢的女孩热烈鼓掌!
Miss Ann Darrow.
安·丹劳小姐
Save me from the beast!
把我从野兽手上救出来!
Help me!
救我!
Where is she?
她在哪里?
- Where's Ann?   - I have no idea.
- 安在哪里?  - 我不知道
I heard he offered her all kinds of money and she turned him down flat.
我听说他们出一大笔钱  但她干脆地拒绝了
∮ Pack up all ny cares and woe. ∮
∮ 整理好我所有的烦恼和悲哀 ∮
∮ Here I go. ∮
∮ 我来了 ∮
∮ singing low. ∮
∮ 低声吟唱 ∮
∮ Bye bye. ∮
∮ 再见 ∮
∮ Blackbird. ∮
∮ 黑鸟 ∮
∮ Where sonebody waits for ne. ∮
∮ 是什么地方有个人在等我 ∮
∮ sugar's sweet. ∮
∮ 糖很甜 ∮
∮ so is he. ∮
∮ 他也一样 ∮
∮ Bye bye. ∮
∮ 再见 ∮
∮ Blackbird. ∮
∮ 黑鸟 ∮
here's your story, boys.
这就是你们的故事  先生们
"Beauty and the man who saved her from the beast."
"美女和从野兽手里拯救他的男人"
No.
不
We have to get these people out of here.
我们赶快把人弄出去
Everyone needs to leave, okay? Come on.
所有人出去了  走吧
Let him roar. It makes a swell picture.
让他吼吧  这镜头很精彩
Head for the exits.
往出口走
Get your own seat, buddy. You're not having mine.
你自己买座位  伙计  别打我的主意
Excuse me, fellows.
借光  伙计
Coming through. Coming through, fellows.
好戏来了  来了  伙计们
Get me down! Help me, please!
救我下来!救命!求你!
Somebody! Somebody help me!
来人啊!来人救救我!
Go! Go! Get out!
走!走!出去!
Go! Go!
走啊!走啊!
There they are. Come on, come with me.
他们在那儿!
- Go!   - Wait for me!
- 走啊!  - 等等我!
Go back!
回去!
This way!
走这边!
Help!
救命!
No!
不!
Taxi! Follow that ape.
出租车  跟着那只猩猩
Come on, pal, we gotta draw him off.
来吧  老兄  我们要转移他的注意力
It's all yours, buddy.
这车是你的了  伙计
Better get out of here, lady!
嘿  离开这  女士!
Come on.
来啊
Buddy!
伙计!
Come on. Come on.
来啊!来啊!
Look out.
当心
Jesus Christ.
耶稣基督啊
Fire!
开火!
Stop!
住手!
Listen up.
听着
This is New York City, and this is sacred ground.
这里是纽约  是神圣的地方
You hear me?
你听见我说的了?
It was built for humans, by humans.
这里是人类建造的  也是为人类建造的
Not for stinking lice-infested apes.
不是给长虱子的臭猩猩建的
The thought of sone nutant gorilla...
如果一只变种猩猩想...
crapping all over the streets of this fair city, fills ne with disgust.
踩烂这座美丽城市的每一寸土地都会令我厌恶
So this is how it's gonna be.
所以这就是后果
We find it. We kill it.
我们找到它  我们就杀了它
We cut its ugly head off and we ram it up...
砍掉它丑陋的头颅  砸碎它...
No. No.
不!不!
Beautiful.
真美丽!
Yes.
是的!
Yes, it is.
是的!很美!
Hey! Hey!
嘿!嘿!
Nobody past this point.
禁止通行!
You can't go in there!
你不能进去!
Hey!
嘿!
Stop him!
抓住他!
Hey! Get back. You're not allowed up there!
嘿!回来!你不能进来!
- What's going on?   - Go!
- 怎么回事?  - 快走!
No!
不!
Please! No!
求你!不!
No!
不!
Ann. Ann.
安!安!
Move along.
走开!
Just one shot! One shot!
就拍一下  拍一下!
- Come, come!   - Boys, how about a photo?
- 过来  过来!  - 伙计们  照张相怎么样?
Look at me.
看着我
Come on, watch the camera.
来吧  看着相机
Come a little closer.
站得再近一点
That's it, folks. Show's over. Step back!
好了  伙计们  完事了  退后
Clear the area. That's it. Shove off, boys.
清理现场  就这样  退后  兄弟们
Why'd he do that?
为什么它要那样?
Climb up there and get himself cornered.
爬那么高  把自己困住了
The ape must have known what was coming.
猩猩肯定知道是什么下场
He's just a dumb animal. Didrt know nothing.
它就是个蠢动物  啥都不懂
What does it matter? Airplanes got him.
有什么区别?飞机收拾了它
It wasrt the airplanes.
不是飞机
It was beauty killed the beast.
是美女杀死了野兽